The rousing, rollicking adventure of the world's first rockin' rooster!
Rock-A-Doodle is a comedy, family, animation film directed by Don Bluth.
Chanticleer is a foolhardy farm rooster who believes his crows
can actually make the sun come up and shine.
When the sun rises one morning without Chanticleer's crow, he leaves the farm
in disgrace and runs off to become a rock 'n' roll singer.
But in his absence, a sinister, sunshine-hating owl prepares to take over.
Chanticleer / The King (voice), played by Glen Campbell.
Edmond, played by Toby Scott Ganger.
Grand Duke (voice), played by Christopher Plummer.
Dory - Mother, played by Kathryn Holcomb.
Frank - Dad, played by Stan Ivar.
Goldie (voice), played by Ellen Greene.
Rock-a-Doodle is a 1991 independent animated musical comedy film produced by
Sullivan Bluth Studios Ireland Limited and Goldcrest Films.
Loosely based on Edmond Rostand's 1910 comedy play Chantecler,
Rock-a-Doodle was directed by Don Bluth and written by David N.
The film features the voices of Christopher Plummer, Phil Harris (in his final film role), Glen Campbell, Sorrell Booke,
Sandy Duncan, Eddie Deezen, Ellen Greene, Charles Nelson Reilly, and Toby Scott Ganger (in his film debut).
The film tells the story of an anthropomorphic rooster named Chanticleer,
who lives on a farm and crows every morning to raise the sun.
However, he leaves his farm to become a singer in the city after being tricked by the Grand Duke of Owls,
whose kind hates sunshine, into thinking that his crow does not actually raise the sun.
Without Chanticleer, rain continues to pour non-stop,
causing a massive flood all over the country.
The Duke and his henchmen take over in the darkness, and
plan to eat all of the barnyard animals.
Chanticleer's friends from the farm, along with Edmond, a young human boy who was transformed into a kitten by the Duke,
take off on a mission to get Chanticleer to bring back the sun and save the country before it is too late.
Rock-a-Doodle was released in the United Kingdom on 2 August 1991
and in the United States and Canada on 3 April 1992.
The film received mostly negative reviews and was a box-office
failure, grossing $11 million on a budget of $18 million.
Nevertheless, it would achieve greater success on home video and
obtained popularity among many 1990s children.
The film explores themes of cat, chicken, villain,
rooster, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.